-再来两杯 -马上来
-Two more. -Coming right up.
巴基真走运
Bucky's got all the luck.
是 她很漂亮
Yeah, she's pretty.
我不是说那个 这个幸运儿明天出征
No, not that. Lucky bastard's shipping out tomorrow.
他会距离德国鬼子一步之遥
He's gonna be a stone's throw away from the Krauts,
而我们其他人却还在 内布拉斯加州进行飞行训练
while the rest of us will still be flying practice missions over Nebraska.
别担心 我们很快就会去那边丢炸弹了
Don't worry. We'll be over there dropping bombs soon enough.
-是 -巴基 下一轮我们请
-Yeah. -Bucky, next round's on us.
他从没请过
He's never done that before.
所以你是巴基 他是巴克
So you're Bucky, and he's Buck?
说来话长
It's a long story.
他们这对好甜蜜啊 我真该早些介绍他们认识的
They make a nice pair, don't they? I should have introduced them earlier.
他明天就要走了
He's leaving tomorrow.
人人都需要在故乡有个写信的对象
Everyone needs someone to write to back home.
我不知道约翰伊根是不是爱写信的那种人
I don't know if John Egan's the pen pal type.
也许他认识了 值得写信的女孩 他就爱写了
Well, maybe if he met a girl worth writing to, he would be.
值得写信的女孩凤毛麟角
Well, a girl worth writing to is hard to find.
远在天边 近在眼前
Not if you know where to look.
我懂了
I see what you mean.
那你会给我写信吗
So, you'll write me?
我已经写了
Well, I already have.
你给我写了封信
You wrote me a letter?
对
Yeah.
写了些什么
What's it say?
那你得等收到才知道了
Well, you'll have to wait and find out.
那是什么时候呢
Well, when will that be?
等我出发后两三周吧
When I ship out. I'd say two or three weeks.
我会无时无刻地想念你
I'm gonna miss you every second.
好了 先生们 我来敬酒
All right, all right. Gentlemen, a toast.
巴克 玛姬 嘿 你们这对鸳鸯 我们要给巴基敬酒了
Buck, Marge--hey, you lovebirds--we're toasting Bucky over here.
注意 伊根少校
Hear, hear, Major Egan.
-敬我们新的航空军官 巴基 -嘿
-To our new Air Exec, Bucky. -Hey, hey.
好的 少校
All right, Major.
100大队醉鬼中的佼佼者
Of all the drunks in the 100th.
总得有人带领你们这些笨蛋
Well, someone's got to make a nest for the rest of you dodos.
-干杯 少校 -敬100大队
-Cheers, Major. -To the 100th.
-对 敬100轰炸大队 -祝好运 长官
-Yeah, to the 100th. -Best of luck, sir.
-谢谢 -给我们留点德国鬼子
-Thanks. -Save some Krauts for us.
我们要去斯路特 你们来吗
We're going to Slooter's. You guys coming?
不了 我一大早就要飞了
Nah, I gotta fly early.
-巴克 -不了 各位
-Buck? -I don't think so, boys.
那明天见 拜拜 玛姬
See you tomorrow then. Bye, Marge.
巴基 英格兰见
Bucky, see you in England.
记住 我要多来几条毯子 和一个有风景的铺位
And remember, I want extra blankets and a cot with a view.
没问题
Consider it done.
他不肯告诉我 这些外号是怎么回事
He won't tell me. What's with the nicknames?
说嘛 玛姬
Spill, Marge.
-可以吗 -说吧
-Yeah? -Go ahead.
-好 -都说了说来话长
-Okay. -Told you, it's a long story.
他们是在战前基础训练期间认识的
Well, they met in basic training before the war started.
约翰从小的外号就是巴基
John was always Bucky since he was a kid.
-对吧 -没错 对
-Right? -That's right, yeah.
盖尔 一直叫盖尔
And Gale--Well, Gale's always been Gale.
直到
Until...
基础训练第一天 这家伙走过来
First day of basic training, this fella walks up to me
说我让他想起了老家 威斯康星州的一个家伙
and says that I remind him of a guy back home in Wisconsin,
那个人叫巴克
goes by the name of Buck.
我跟他说我叫盖尔 克莱文
I tell him my name's Gale, Gale Cleven.
然后 但这位巴基不管不顾
And--But Bucky here, he's not deterred.
没错 他总是叫我“巴克”
No, sir. It's just "Buck this, Buck that."
“巴克 帮我系鞋带好吗”“巴克 帮我开这架飞机”
"Buck, can you help me tie my shoes?" "Buck, help me fly this plane."
没过多久
Before I know it,
整个第8航空队都叫我巴克了 所以
the whole damn Eighth Air Force is calling me Buck. So...
盖尔算哪门子名字啊
What kind of a name is Gale anyway?
知道吗 你该谢我 我帮了你个忙
You know what? You should actually be thanking me. I did you a favor.
-谢你给我起了和你一样的名字 -并不完全一样
-For giving me the same name as you? -It's not exactly the same name,
而且这不是我的错 谁叫你看起来和巴克一模一样
and it's not my fault you look exactly like Buck
-他来自威斯康星马尼托沃克 -马尼托沃克
-from Manitowoc, Wisconsin. -From Manitowoc.
怎能这样对待自己最好的朋友啊
What kind of man does that to his best friend?
-真甜蜜 -我们需要音乐
-It's so sweet. -We need music.
好 别走开 盖尔
Okay. Don't go away, Gale--
巴克 你在今晚结束前得跟我跳舞
Buck. You're gonna dance with me before this night is through.
别逼我跳舞 玛姬
Don't make me dance, Marge.
选首好听的
Pick a good one.
亚提萧 本尼古德曼
Artie Shaw, Benny Goodman.
嘿 我很惊讶我们竟然是朋友
Hey. You know, I am amazed that we're friends.
你不喜欢和美女跳舞
You don't like to dance with a beautiful woman.
你不喝酒 不赌博
You don't drink. You don't gamble.
你甚至不喜欢体育比赛
You don't even like sports.
我们是生命中最神秘的物种之一
Well, we are one of life's great mysteries.
-我超爱这首 好 -是吗
-I love that. Yes. -Yeah?
那么要告别了
So this is it.
要告别了
This is it.
几周后见
I'll see you in a few weeks.
如果我没先挂掉的话
If I don't die first.
我不想提醒你 巴基 但你现在是100轰炸大队的航空军官
Hate to break it to you, Bucky, but you are the 100th's Air Executive now.
你不是去那边执行飞行任务的
You're not going over there to fly missions.
听着 我和389大队的指挥官聊过
Look, I had a conversation with the CO over at the 389th,
在你们来之前 我要跟他们一起出飞行任务
and I'm flying with those boys until you guys show up.
我会当观察飞行员
I'll be an observation pilot.
你这个混蛋
You son of a bitch.
总得有人尝尝战斗的滋味
Yeah. Well, someone's gotta taste a little combat,
告诉你们实战是怎么回事吧
tell you what it's really like up there.
在我到那里前 你不许死
Well, don't you die on me before I get over there.
那可没准
Don't count on it.
压住机鼻 把火扑灭
Keep your nose down! Let's get this fire out!
快 再快点 帮帮忙啊
Come on, faster! You have to help us!
(1943年5月21日 389轰炸大队)
(德国 威廉港)
好 火灭了
That's it! The fire is out!
拉起来
Pull! Pull up! Up!
再使点劲儿拉
Harder!
好 拉平了 还差一点
Okay, leveling out! Almost there!
-战斗机 12点方向 正前方 -糟糕
-Fighters, 12:00! Dead ahead! -Oh, shit!
第四襟翼坏了
We've lost the fourth flap.
飞行员呼叫导航员
Pilot to navigator.
我们必须返航 需要新航向
We gotta head back. We need a new heading!
该死
Fuck!
我是杜瓦尔
This is Duval.
我中弹了
And I've been hit.
我下来找你 杜瓦尔
I'm coming down to you, Duval.
向正西飞
Point it due west.
收到 二号引擎正在失去油压
Roger! We're losing oil pressure on engine two!
稳住 我会找个新航向
Keep it steady and I'll get a new heading.
深呼吸 哥们 坚持住
Breathe, man! Just breathe! Hang on!
-杜瓦尔 你哪里中弹了 -该死
-Duval! Where are you hit? -Fuck.
坚持住 杜瓦尔
Stay with me, Duval!
我陪着你呢
I'm right here.
-我会死的 巴基 -别说了 杜瓦尔 你会活下去的
-I'm not gonna make it, Bucky. -Stop it, Duval. You're gonna make it.
用手按住伤口 这里 很好
Put your hand on the wound. Here. That's good.
-好 -好了 坚持住 见鬼
-Okay. Okay. -All right? Stay with me, goddamn it!
听见没 看着我 睁开眼睛
You hear me? Look at me! Open your eyes! Open your eyes!
呼吸
Breathe, breathe, breathe!
战斗机 12点方向
Fighters, 12:00!
打中一架
Got one!
伊根 我需要新航向
Egan, I need that heading!
新航向 向左转到248
New heading: Turn left at 248.
收到
Roger!
加油 坚持住
Come on. Stay with me.
-我们要回家了 -好
-We're headed home. -Yeah. Yeah.
继续呼吸
Just keep breathing!
这次观察任务真了不得 少校
That was a hell of an observation mission, Major.
这些任务都是这样
Are they all like that?
你在想怎么跟弟兄们说
You wondering what to tell your guys?
什么也别说 他们会自己弄明白的
Don't say anything. They'll figure it out.
我们都一样
We all do.
(根据唐纳德L.米勒的著作改编)
空战群英
第一季第一集
第 一 集
100轰炸大队于1943年春被派往英格兰
The 100th bomb group was sent to England in the spring of 1943
加入美国陆军第8航空队 与纳粹德国作战
to join the US Army's Eighth Air Force in its battle against Nazi Germany.
我说 就管这空中堡垒 叫达拉斯的爱丽丝吧
I say we call this fort Alice From Dallas.
达拉斯的爱丽丝
Alice From Dallas?
挺上口的
It's got a ring to it.
达拉斯的爱丽丝 我们的爱丽丝宫殿
Alice From Dallas. Alice, our palace.
给克莱文少校看看
Show Major Cleven.
洛奇 给少校看看
Lorch, show the major.
要还给我啊
I want her back.
这女士可厉害了 起她的名 这空中堡垒如虎添翼
Hell of a dame. She'll give this fort a little extra muscle.
(肯 平安归来 爱你 爱丽丝)
我明白你为什么 要用她的名字命名堡垒了
I see why you'd wanna name this fort after her.
-她很特别 -她很厉害
-She's special. -She's formidable.
埃米森 你确定你没指错峡湾
Amison, you sure you got us to the right fjord?
确定 百分百正确
Roger. 100%.
纳丁 后面情况如何
Nutting, how we looking back there?
阵型良好 长官
Eight in a line, sir.
收到
Roger.
我们大多数人从未出过远门
Most of us had never traveled far from home,
更别提乘飞机了
let alone flown in an airplane.
我们为了一个共同目标 从这个国家的四面八方汇集于此
We came from every corner of the country, with a common purpose:
来讨伐希特勒
to bring the war to Hitler's doorstep.
飞行员呼叫机组 我们很快就会在格陵兰降落
Pilot to crew. We'll be touching down in Greenland shortly
吃点东西 休息一下
to get some chow and some rest.
布朗迪塔台 这里是陆军233号 一队B17轰炸机正在布鲁伊西一号上空
Blondie Tower, Army 233. A flight of B-17s over Bluie West One.
请告知降落指示
Landing instructions, please.
陆军233号 这里是布朗迪塔台
Army 233, flight Blondie Tower.
请用六号跑道 可以降落
Continue for runway six. Clear to land.
天空无云 能见度良好 风向330 时速64公里 阵风时速80公里
Sky CAVU. Winds 330 at 40, gusting to 50.
测高仪2990
Altimeter 2-niner-niner-0.
有点小风
It's a little breezy.
小风 在阿拉巴马州 我们管这叫飓风
Breezy? In 'Bama, we call that a hurricane.
收到 布朗迪塔台 继续向六号跑道飞 天空无云 能见度良好
Roger, Blondie Tower. Continuing to runway six. Sky CAVU.
风向330 时速64公里 阵风时速80公里
Winds of 330 to 40, gusting to 50.
侧风很猛 阵风在变强 各位 小心
Hell of a crosswind. Gusts increasing, fellas. Be careful.
也许可以盘旋一阵子 少校 欢迎来到格陵兰
You might want to circle around, Major. Welcome to Greenland.
放下起落架 准备襟翼
Landing gear down. Get ready on flaps.
正在放下起落架
Landing gear coming down.
会很颠簸的 各位 扶稳
It's gonna get bumpy. Hang on, guys.
飞行员呼叫机组 准备降落
Pilot to crew. Prepare for landing.
左起落架已放下
Left gear down.
右起落架已放下
Right's down.
最后进近检查 襟翼开启四分之一
Final-approach checks. Flaps at quarter?
对 襟翼开启四分之一
Yeah. Flaps at quarter.
-襟翼开启一半 -襟翼开启一半
-Flaps at half. -Flaps are half.
襟翼收起
Flaps up.
搞定
Got 'em.
你得拉起来 维尔 再绕一圈
You gotta pull up, Veal. Come back around.
(南格陵兰 布鲁伊西一号机场)
Our unit was made up of four squadrons.
我们的部队由四个中队组成
盖尔克莱文少校是350中队的指挥官
Major Gale Cleven was the commander of the 350th.
他和伊根少校是我们整个部队中
He and Major Egan were the unquestioned leaders
毋容置疑的领导者
of our entire group.
艾弗布莱克利是来自西雅图的飞行员
Ev Blakely was a pilot from Seattle.
-瞧瞧是谁来了 -布莱克利
-Look who it is. -Blakely.
洒脱的本尼德马科来自费城
And big-hearted Benny DeMarco, from Philly.
-少校 -德马科
-Major. -DeMarco.
-这降落真要命 -见过更糟的
-Hell of a landing. -Seen worse.
-是说那次空战吗 -对
-Is that the fight? -Yeah.
-克雷特 你下注了吧 -是的
-Claytor, you got money on this, right? -I do.
-信号真差 哥们 -是 还用说嘛
-It's bad signal though, man. -Yeah, you don't say.
调大点声
Well, turn it up.
投弹手詹姆斯道格拉斯 和霍华德汉密尔顿来自中西部
Bombardiers James Douglass and Howard Hamilton were from the Midwest.
汉勃恩
Hambone.
-少校 -好
-Major. -Yep.
冷静点 我能行
Calm down. I got it.
还有查尔斯克鲁克香克 又叫克兰克 来自新英格兰
And Charles Cruikshank, also known as Crank, was from New England.
你好 克兰克 听说你们降落得很不平稳
Hiya, Crank. Heard you boys had a rough landing.
我和我最好的朋友 “泡泡”乔佩恩都是导航员
My best friend Joe "Bubbles" Payne and I were navigators,
所以地理位置对我们很重要
so location was important to us.
少校 克罗斯比尉官
Major? Lieutenant Crosby.
你是哪里人 是这样 我们要在地图上插大头针
Where are you from? Yeah, we gotta put a pin in it.
我和泡泡 对 在保持这项传统
Bubbles and I--we're, yeah, you know, keeping the tradition alive.
-兄弟们来自全国各地 -是
-Got guys from all parts. -Yeah.
怀俄明州 卡斯珀
Casper, Wyoming.
-牛仔之州啊 -是
-Cowboy State, huh? -Yep.
看起来你是第一个从这儿来的人 少校
Well, it looks like you're the first, Major.
(怀俄明州)
好吧
How about that.
少校 喝点什么
Major. What can I get for ya?
几周前 我有个朋友从这里经过
A buddy of mine came through here some weeks ago.
飞行大队航空军官 当时出了一个状况
Group Air Exec. There was an incident.
你是伊根的朋友 约翰伊根少校 巴基
You friends with Egan? Major John Egan? Bucky?
是的 好吧
I am. Yeah.
无论他说了什么 我没错
Whatever he said, I didn't do anything wrong.
不 他只是想让我把这个交给你
No, he just wanted me to give you this.
说这是替代品
Said it's a replacement.
替代品
A replacement?
对
Yeah.
这怎么能算替代品
And how exactly is this supposed to be a replacement?
中士 我不知道出了什么事
Sergeant, I don't know what went on,
但他跟我说这个应该可以补偿
but he told me that that should make up for it.
看见那个了吗
You see that?
独角鲸的断角 他把那个角 从墙上拿下来 假装独角兽
Broken narwhal tusk? He pulled it down off the wall, pretended to be a unicorn.
捅破了我的两张沙发 打碎了酒吧里几乎所有的杯子
Ripped two of my couches, broke almost every glass in the bar.
我明白了
I see.
通常我能看出谁是捣蛋鬼
You know, usually I can spot a troublemaker,
但你朋友似乎挺好
but your friend seemed fine.
直到他开始唱歌
Till he started to sing.
对 听起来很像他的作风
Yeah, that sounds about right.
我要她给我加分 她拒绝了我
I asked her for credit She answered me nay
像你这样的顾客我随时都可能遇到
Such a customer as you I can have any day
-不行 没戏 休想 -你不必这样的
-And it's no, nay, never -You don't have to do this.
只是个愚蠢的赌注
It's a stupid bet.
-不行 没戏 休想 不要了 -我不能怂
-No, nay, never, no more -I have to now.
-我会不会 -谁来
-Will I play---Who's it gonna be?
-好了 -谁来
-All right, all right. -Who's it gonna be?
我跟你们所有人都比过
Now, I've played every one of ya...
你们这些爱尔兰人射中靶心的水平
and you Irish are about as good at hitting that bull's-eye
和你们敲钉子差不多
as you are at hammering your nails.
不知道你们笑什么 你们英国人没好多少
I don't know why you're laughing. You English ain't much better.
杰克
Jack!
但这位汤米 是整个东英吉利的
But Tommy here, Tommy here is the best damn dart slinger
-最佳飞镖手 -你会瞎一只眼的
-in the whole of East Anglia! -You'll lose an eye.
不会的 我相信汤米
No, I won't. I trust Tommy.
如果他赢了 两辆脚踏车都归我
Now, he wins this, I get both those bikes.
好 赌就赌 美国佬
Yeah. You're on, Yank.
-两辆 -好 两辆
-Both of 'em. -All right, both of them.
我还要一个吻
And I get a kiss.
好 汤米 别打到我的眼睛 汤米 好吗
All right, Tommy. Not my eyes. Not my eyes, Tommy. All right?
加油 汤米
Come on, Tommy.
好 汤米 准备好就投吧
All right, Tommy. Whenever you're ready.
我输掉两辆脚踏车 汤米
I just lost two bloody bikes, Tommy.
-你怎么回事 -汤米
-What's the matter with you? -Tommy!
我的眼里只有蓝天
Nothing but blue skies Do I see
(1943年6月8日 英格兰 东英吉利)
不过不是在英格兰 这里有烂天气和蓝天
Not in England though Got shitty weather and blue skies
对着我微笑
Smiling at me
(未经许可不得入内)
(皇家空军 索普阿伯特)
-晚上好 少校 那脚踏车卖吗 -给多少钱都不卖
-Evening, Major. Is that bike for sale? -Not for all the money in the world.
我的职责是把布雷迪上尉和其他机组人员
It was my job to get Captain Brady and the rest of our crew
从格陵兰引导到 我们在英格兰索普阿伯特的基地
from Greenland to our base at Thorpe Abbotts in England.
但不知何故 我们和机群
But somehow, we were separated from the rest of our group
在大西洋上空的云层中飞散了
in the clouds over the Atlantic.
完全没有能见度已经很难了
Tough enough with zero visibility,
但我有另一个问题 控制不住的晕机
but I had another problem: uncontrollable air sickness.
我们有电路问题
We have an electrical problem.
我们需要航向
We need a heading.
克罗斯比 你在听吗
Crosby, you there?
抱歉 能重复一遍吗
Sorry. Could you repeat that?
电路出故障了
We got a gremlin in the electrical.
在我们修理的时候 给我们一个等待航线 克罗斯
Give us a holding pattern while we figure this out, Croz.
收到 稍等
Roger. Stand by.
向右转到165 完毕
Turn right to 165. Over.
收到 向右转到165
Roger. Turning right to 165.
关闭电路 重新启动 我们来把它修好
Shutting off electrical and recycling it. Let's fix this.
一定是某一条控制电路
It's gotta be one of the control circuits.
我来拔出保险丝 这样能把故障单独隔离
I'll pull the fuses. That'll isolate the problem.
好 去吧
Right. Go.
你怎么还在吐
How are you still vomiting?
你的胃应该和我们的油箱一样空了
Your stomach's gotta be as empty as our fuel tank.
是
Yeah, yeah.
-该死的 克罗斯 -对不起
-Oh, gosh darn it, Croz. -I'm sorry.
弄了我一身 给我拿块布来
It's all over me. Get me a rag.
-对不起 -快点
-I'm sorry, I'm sorry. -Come on.
臭死了
It stinks.
快点 搞定没
Come on. You got it?
我没看到有什么故障 也许是轮子马达的问题
No gremlin as far as I can see. Maybe a problem with the wheel motor.
重启电池和发电机
Restarting batteries and generators.
恢复了
Back on.
警报灯灭了
Warning lights off.
这是英格兰的海岸线吗 克罗斯比 这是英格兰吧
Is that the coast of England? Crosby, that's England, right?
不 我们不该在水面上空的 尉官
No, we shouldn't be over water, Lieutenant.
长官 航向是什么
Sir, what's your heading?
165 就像你说的
165, like you told me.
老天啊
Oh, good Lord in Heaven.
混蛋 这是法国
Son of a bitch. That's France!
飞行员呼叫机组 前方有高射炮 扶稳了 该死
Pilot to crew, flak ahead. Hold on. Shit!
该死的 克罗斯
Goddamn it, Croz.
(索普阿伯特空军基地)
莫里斯 谢谢你的脚踏车
Morris. Thanks for the bikes.
我下次会赢你的
I'll get you next time.
来吧 就这样 很好
Come on. There you go, lovely.
继续往那边走 快走 小家伙
Keep that way. Go on, girl.
他们来了
Here they come.
走吧 小家伙
Come on, boy.
德马科
DeMarco!
嗨 少校
Hey, Major.
本尼 你哪弄来的狗啊
Where did you get that dog, Benny?
玩花旗骰赢的
I won him at craps.
你把这小宝贝带到了三千米以上的高空
You took this baby above 10,000 feet.
它有氧气面罩 我花3块钱买的 但它可真喜欢飞行啊
He's got a mask. It cost me three bucks. But boy, he loves to fly.
-嚎叫个不停 -因为它身上流着狼的血液
-He wouldn't stop howling. -That's because he's part wolf.
是这只狼身上流着狗的血
That wolf's part dog.
-它叫什么 -肉丸
-Got a name? -Meatball.
欢迎来到100轰炸大队 肉丸
Welcome to the 100th, Meatball.
走吧 肉丸
Come on, Meatball.
想我了吗
You miss me?
想你才怪
Like a stone in my shoe.
-最近怎么样 -有一半装备还没运到
-How you been getting on? -Half our equipment's yet to show up.
不得不向英国人借面罩和降落伞
Had to borrow masks and parachutes from the Brits.
这是航空军官的职责
Air Exec ought to take care of that.
依我看 他们应该把他撤掉
My opinion: They ought to can the guy.
还有 习惯一下泥巴吧
Also, get used to the mud.
嘿 听着 你的通讯员 有没有收到418大队的消息
Hey, listen, your radio guy pick up any chatter from the 418th?
布雷迪还没到
We're missing Brady.
没有
Negative.
我给你弄了辆脚踏车
I got you a bike.
我需要脚踏车吗
I need a bike?
否则从营房走到食堂要20分钟
Or it's a 20-minute walk from the quarters to the mess.
这些宝贝卖断货好几周了
And these things are sold out for weeks.
我想你能超过不少在雨中为了去吃晚饭
I figure you'll buzz past a bunch of guys crawling through the rain
步履维艰的人
on the way to dinner.
你到时候就会回来说 “谢谢你 巴基”
You'll come around and say, "Thank you, Bucky."
你别指望了
Don't count on it.
布雷迪来了
Well, there's Brady.
好 再检查一次起落架 放下来
Okay, let's check the landing gear. Bring it down.
收到
Roger.
左起落架下来了
Left coming down.
尾部起落架放下了
Tail down.
右侧的没放下
Negative on right.
该死
Fuck.
右轮卡住了 下不来
Right wheel won't come down.
-布卢姆 用手摇曲柄 -好
-Blum, get on the manual crank. -I'm on it.
哈弗 你去帮他
Hafer, you help him out.
收到 遵命
Roger, wilco.
拿着
Take that.
曲柄在哪
Where's the crank?
快
Come on.
摇不动
It won't budge.
-拜托 -我在努力了
-Come on. -I'm trying.
快 让开 我来
Come on. Get out of the way. Come on. Give it here.
-你抓住了 -是
-You got it? -Yeah.
起落架马达一定是烧坏了 或者千斤顶螺丝卡住了
The landing gear motor must be fried or the jackscrew's jammed up.
-你确定 -是 长官
-You sure? -Yes, sir.
纹丝不动
It's completely frozen.
放不下来
It's not coming down.
把左起落架收起来
Bring the left landing gear up.
你确定
You sure?
确定 用机腹迫降 我们活下来的机会
Yeah, we got a better shot at walking away from a belly landing
比用单轮降落更大
than we do on one wheel.
晴天塔台 这里是陆军071 起落架没响应
Clear-up Tower, this is Army 071. Landing gear not responding.
请告知降落指示 完毕
Requesting landing instructions. Over.
收到 陆军071 可以降落
Roger, Army 071, clear to land.
救援队已就绪 完毕
Rescue crew at the ready. Over.
收到 晴天塔台
Roger, Clear-up.
飞行员呼叫机组 做好迫降准备
Pilot to crew, prepare for crash landing.
听见没 快 动起来
You hear that? Come on. Let's go.
247 紧急人员
247. Emergency personnel...
-好 出去 大家快出去 -快
-Okay. Get out! Everybody out. -Let's go, go, go!
快出去
Get the fuck out of here!
-动起来 -快
-Move! Move! -Go, go, go, go.
快 快点 动起来 快跑 否则你就死了 快
Go, go! Come on! Get a move on. Run now or you're dead. Go, go!
(救护车)
-一切安全 -该死
-All clear. -Oh, fuck.
小意思
Easy deal.
-把它抬起来 挂上牵引绳 -交给我 走吧
-Jack it up and hook it up. -I'm on it. Let's go.
你是导航员 克罗斯比
You're a navigator, Crosby.
怎么说 你应该能找到英格兰的
You should be able to, I don't know, find England.
大家都还好吗
Everyone okay?
-是 长官 -长官
-Yes, sir. -Sir.
布雷迪
Brady.
来我办公室
Step into my office.
你怎么把飞行中队跟丢了
How'd you lose the rest of the squadron?
我们在云层中飞散了
We got separated in clouds.
然后我们遇到了某种电路故障
And then we had some kind of electrical failure,
我们用了一个小时试图放下起落架
so we spent an hour just trying to get the wheel down.
俗话说得好
Well, you know what they say.
作为飞行员
There are two kinds of pilots,
降落时起落架放不下来这种事 早晚都会经历到
those who have had a wheels-up landing and those who will.
少校 其实没那么糟糕
Major, it looks worse than it is.
-好 去把它修好吧 -我这就去办 少校
-All right. Sort it out. -On it, Major.
你不必替我打掩护 好吧
You didn't have to cover for me, okay.
-这是我的责任 我应该 -我不是替你打掩护
-It was my responsibility. I should've---I wasn't covering for you.
我们遇到了机械故障
We had a mechanical failure.
控制一下你晕机的问题
Get a grip on that airsickness.
否则就离开我的机组
Or get off my plane.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
克罗斯 你要选观光路线吗
Croz, you take the scenic route?
你要跟我说说独角兽的事吗
So, you wanna tell me about this unicorn story?
独角兽是已灭绝动物中我最喜欢的
Well, the unicorn is my favorite extinct animal.
法国
France?
-你怎么做到的 -泡泡 还能怎样
-How the hell did you manage that? -How else, Bubbles?
我都快把苦胆吐出来了
Puking my goddamn guts out.
我以为你开始执行任务
I thought that went away
-就不会再晕机了 -对 通常是这样
-once you got going. -No, yeah, it usually does.
但这次有颠簸 就 我也说不好
But this time with the turbulence, it kinda--I don't know.
这次还是晕机了
This time it didn't.
我一定是整个陆军航空部队中 最差劲的导航员了
I gotta be the worst navigator in the entire Army Air Force.
克罗斯比 一定有人比你更差劲
Oh, Crosby, there's gotta be somebody worse.
-至少得有一个 -嘿
-At least one. -Hey.
走错边了 尉官
Wrong side of the road, Lieutenant.
-长官 -欢迎来到英格兰
-Sir. -Welcome to England.
要我说 这两位看《试飞员》
Now, you ask me, those two have watched Test Pilot
看了太多次了
a few too many times.
你才看《试飞员》 太多次了
You watched Test Pilot a few too many times.
是 没什么帮助
Yeah. Didn't help.
至少是由我们告诉他们飞机该往哪边飞
Well, at least we get to tell 'em which direction to point the plane.
-回见 巴克 -谢谢
-See ya, Buck. -Thanks for the lift.
通常是直达航线 在你这里则是观光航线
Normally the direct route. In your case, the scenic route.
观光航线 真好笑
The scenic route? Very funny.
(100轰炸大队指挥官 哈罗德Q.胡格林上校办公室)
我认为我不必向你解释
I wouldn't have assumed I'd need to explain to you
你的责任有多重大
the gravity of your responsibilities.
你清楚此事和你的机组 把床铺收拾得多整洁无关
You are aware this isn't just about how well your crews make their beds.
是 长官
I am, sir.
所以我强调的是飞行 而不是叠被子
Which is why I prioritize the flying more than their folding.
35架飞机和350名机组人员都归你管
You are in charge of 35 planes and 350 aircrewmen.
这些小伙子还没有实战经验
Boys who have yet to experience combat.
他们能否活命 取决于命令 纪律和你的榜样
Their lives depend on order and discipline and your example.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
恕我直言
With all due respect...
我觉得我对你和他们更有用的角色
I think I would be of more use to them and you
是中队指挥官 而不是航空军官
as a squadron commander, rather than an Air Exec.
你在人前挥舞指挥棒
Just because you spin the baton at the front
并不意味着你就是团队领导
doesn't make you the band leader.
我只是觉得我不适合坐办公室
I just don't think I was made to sit behind a desk.
我得在天上帮兄弟们战斗
I need to be up there helping my guys.
勒梅上校盯上我们了
Colonel LeMay has us in his sights.
他迫不及待想要终结100轰炸大队
And he's just itching to pull the trigger on the 100th Bomb Group.
我负责期间不会让这种事发生
That's not gonna happen on my watch.
我希望所有的军官跟我齐心协力
And I expect all officers to get in the game with me.
也包括你 伊根少校
That means you, Major Egan.
你可以走了
You're dismissed.
长官 你还好吗 要我叫医生吗
You okay, sir? Should I call the doctor?
我没事
I'm all right.
(1943年6月25日 凌晨3点)
刚过了几天 他们在半夜把我们叫醒 执行第一次任务
Within days, they woke us up for our first mission.
(军官营房)
我们在美国进行过几百小时的飞行训练
With hundreds of hours of flight training in the States,
不得不相信自己已经准备好了
we had to believe we were prepared.
我们别无选择 因为现在是实战了
We had to, because now it was real.
长官 你今天要飞任务
Sir. Sir, you're flying today.
克莱文少校 长官
Major Cleven, sir.
出任务的日子总是有一顿特别的早餐
There was always a special breakfast on mission days:
鸡蛋 法国吐司 煎饼 双份的培根
eggs, French toast, flapjacks, double rations of bacon,
鲜榨葡萄柚汁和几杯美军咖啡
fresh grapefruit juice and a couple of cups of GI coffee.
士兵们称之为最后的晚餐
The men would come to call it the last supper.
我希望我们都能平安归
I hope we all we get back okay from--
查克 请把盐递给我好吗
Chuck, can you pass the salt, please?
-不好 -糟糕 他把盐弄撒了
-Uh-oh. -Oh, shit. He spilled the salt.
请你把盐从肩膀上方抛过去
Would you please toss the salt over your shoulder,
好让大家继续吃早餐
so we can all get on with our breakfast?
-谁干的 -天啊
-Who did that? -Jesus.
-不是抛整瓶盐 查克 -不会给我们带来霉运
-Not the whole thing, Chuck. -Doesn't bring us bad luck.
是你让我抛盐的
You said toss the salt.
白痴
Moron.
他让我抛盐的
He said toss the salt.
-科特 我今天跟你一起飞 -给
-Curt, I'm flying with you today. -Here you go.
-什么 -抱歉 迪克
-You're what? -Sorry, Dick.
我知道这样你就得在机尾了 但你至少能还击
I know that puts you in the tail, but at least you'll be able to shoot back.
-没关系 -肉丸也在整装待发
-It's all right. -Is Meatball saddling up?
莱蒙斯或温克会照顾它的
Lemmons or Wink will watch him.
这次任务可不好玩 小家伙 我保证
You don't wanna go on this one, buddy. I promise you.
趁着鸡蛋还没被抢光 我最好去弄点
Well, I better get some of those eggs before they're all gone.
别麻烦了 巴克
No, don't bother, Buck.
这些鸡蛋可能是 我青春期那个年代生出来的
These eggs were hatched and powdered before my balls dropped.
好吧 那我不吃了
All right. I'll pass on the eggs then.
-早 小伙子们 -维尔少校 早 长官
-Morning, boys. -Major Veal. Morning, sir.
你们睡得怎么样
How'd you sleep?
-好极了 -睡得很香
-Fucking great. -Like a fucking baby.
新指挥官跟我们一起飞
The new CO flying with us?
新指挥官还是最新指挥官
The new CO, or the new, new CO?
别担心指挥官了 担心自己的任务吧
Don't worry about the CO. Worry about your flying.
我要你们保持密集队形
I want formation so damn tight
机翼之间连一个硬币都塞不过去
you wouldn't be able to slip a dime through our wingtips.
-是 维尔少校 -是 长官
-Yes, sir, Major Veal. -Yes, sir.
立正
Ah-ten-hut.
坐下
As you were.
今天的目标是不来梅
The target for today is Bremen.
我们要攻击威悉河上的U艇基地
We'll be hitting the U-boat pens on the Weser River.
听好 我必须再三强调 这个目标极为重要
Now, I cannot stress enough the importance of this target.
光是上个月 我们就被U艇击沉近70艘货船
We lost almost 70 cargo ships to U-boats last month alone.
如果我们不能把物资从美国运到英国
And if we can't get material from the United States to Great Britain,
就无法攻上欧洲大陆
we won't be stepping foot on the continent.
350大队由克莱文少校率领 位于高位
The 350th will be in high position with Major Cleven as lead pilot,
349大队由维尔少校率领 位于低位
and the 349th will be low with Major Veal as lead.
我会和戴尉官一起在前方的351大队
I'll be up front with Lieutenant Dye in the 351st.
列阵后 100轰炸大队将和94 95
After formation, the 100th will join the 94th, the 95th,
和96轰炸大队会合
and the 96th bomber groups.
我们会在后方最低位置
We will be in the low-low.
末端的飞机
Tail-end Charlie.
总共78架重型轰炸机
In a total wing strength of 78 heavy bombers.
-该死 -鲍曼少校是我们的情报官
-Fuck. -Major Bowman, our Intelligence Officer,
接下来由他介绍
will take it from here.
最后由贝克上尉介绍天气状况
And Captain Becker will finish up with the weather.
少校
Major.
谢谢长官
Thank you, sir.
请关灯
Lights, please.
请吧
There you go.
注意海基和陆基高射炮的位置
Note both naval and ground-based flak positions
遍布诺德奈到朗格奥格之间的 弗里西亚群岛
along the Frisian Islands, from Norderney to Langeoog.
在大陆上空 预计会有密集的高射炮从威廉港
Over the mainland, you can expect concentrated flak from Wilhelmshaven,
一直延续到不来梅
all the way down to Bremen.
已确认的火力包括88和105毫米火炮
Identified batteries consist of 88 and 105 millimeter guns
由维尔茨堡雷达导向 也就是说 敌人会追踪你们的位置
guided by Würzburg radar, so they will be tracking you.
导航员和投弹手 这边结束后
Navigators, bombardiers, once we've wrapped up here,
务必去总部听取特别简报
be sure to report to HQ for a specialized briefing.
好 任务起始点在不来梅西北方 这里
Now, your IP is on the northwest side of Bremen, here.
请换目标地图
Target map, please.
从任务起始点开始
From that initial point,
就向目标直线飞行 长度14公里
it's a straight nine-mile run to the target.
这些就是潜艇基地 在河东岸
These are the pens on the east side of the river.
中间这个就是大家的轰炸中心
Now, this central pen here will be your mean point of impact.
到目标前的航向是正北偏218
And your heading on to the run-up will be 218 degrees true.
转弯后立刻沿着河飞
Immediately after the turn, follow the river.
-给 少校 -谢谢
-Here you go, Major. -Thank you.
说吧 科特 你今天的语录是什么
Come on, Curt. What's your quote for the day?
我要像天使一样飞行 而不是像天使一样死去
I'm gonna fly like an angel today, and not die like one.
少校 好像太小了 我穿不上
Major, I think it's too small. I can't get it on.
-谢谢 -好了
-Thanks. -There you go.
巴克 帮我整理一下夹克
Buck, give me a hand with this sheepskin.
好
Yeah.
可以吗 你能行的 我们能行
You good? You got this. We got this.
我喜欢你的剃须水
I like your aftershave.
很好 我希望你今天飞得和我这么近才好
Good. This is how close I want you on my wing today.
-就像我们训练的那样 -是 长官
-Just like we trained for. -Yes, sir.
早上好 先生们
Good morning, gentlemen.
有人可能不认识我 我是特斯卡神父
For those who don't know me, I'm Father Teska.
我就住对面
I'm right across the way--
菲利普斯上尉也是
Captain Phillips too,
如果谁需要找我们的话
if anyone needs us.
谢谢你 神父 我们会记住的
Thank you, Padre. We'll be sure to keep that in mind.
巴克
Buck.
-嗨 -你还好吗
-Hey. -You all right?
很好
Yeah.
这是什么
What's this?
你在结账吗
You settling accounts?
是我的幸运钱
It's my lucky deuce.
你的幸运
Your lucky--
-天啊 约翰 -给 拿去
-Jesus, John. -Here. Take it.
我已经带着它飞过两次任务了 坏过两个轮子
I've gone on two missions with it already. I had two wheels down.
看 撕掉了两个角 一个角代表一次任务 我还活着
Look, two corners bitten off. One for each mission. Here I am.
拿着
Take it.
上车
Get on in here.
就当是幸运符
For luck.
好
All right.
回头见
See you later.
-好 -大家回头见
-All right. -See you all later.
我要去那里
That's where I'm going.
(教堂)
都凑过来
Let's circle up.
(狂野货物号)
大家知道 这是我们来这里的第一次任务
As you know, it's our first mission here.
我相信大家都记得训练内容 知道自己的职责
I trust you all to remember your training and know your jobs.
让我们圆满完成任务 把炸弹丢在那些纳粹混蛋的头上
Let's knock one off, and drop bombs on those Nazi fucks,
我们就能提早回家了
and we get to go home early.
是 长官
Yes, sir!
这位少校会和我们一起飞 少校
Major here is gonna be flying with us. Major?
兄弟们 这是我们第一次参加实战
First time in the sawmill, boys.
我们去干掉他们
Let's rack 'em up and knock 'em down.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
好 那我们为什么还站着
All right. Why are we still standing here then?
-迪基 这后面一切可好 -开玩笑吗
-Everything okay back here, Dickie? -Are you kidding?
这里和丽兹酒店的套间一样舒适
It's cozy as a suite at the Ritz.
谢谢
Thank you.
-先生们 -长官
-Gentlemen. -Sir.
你搭我们的飞机是我们的荣幸 长官
We're blessed to have you on our plane, sir.
我感觉上帝的精神与你同在
I feel the spirit of God in you.
是 与我们大家同在 朋友
Yeah, in all of us, pal.
你帮我留着座位呢
You saved my seat.
是
Yeah.
我宁可把座位让给你 也不想让你坐我腿上等着我让开
Rather offer it to you than have you sit on my lap till I move.
准备检查核对表吧
Ready for the checklist.
表格1A
Form 1A?
有
Check.
燃料输送阀和开关
Fuel transfer valves and switches?
两个阀门都是关闭的 开关是关闭的
Both transfer valves are off and switch is off.
中冷器是冷的
Intercoolers are cold.
陀螺仪
Gyros?
燃料关闭开关
Fuel shutoff switches?
四个全部为打开
All four open.
整流罩鱼鳞板
Cowl flaps?
已打开 锁定
Open left and locked.
-节流阀 -节流阀为关闭
-Throttles? -Throttles are closed.
总开关和点火开关
Master and ignition switches?
电池已开启
Batteries on.
确认
And check.
增压泵和压力
Booster pumps, pressure?
泵已开启
Pumps on.
燃料量很好
Fuel quantity, good.
好 尉官 你来启动引擎吧
All right, Lieutenant, you ready to start engines?
是 长官
Yes, sir.
启动一号
Start one.
有你在真好 上校
Good to have you with us, Colonel.
-启动二号 -启动二号
-Start two. -Start two.
(狂野货物号)
燃料压力和油压正常
Fuel pressure, oil pressure looking good.
启动三号
Start three.
B17轰炸机配有12挺机枪 提供全方位的防护
The B-17 had 12 machine guns protecting us from every side.
我们称之为飞行堡垒
We called it the Flying Fortress.
但我们存活的关键是要抱团
But the key to our survival was sticking together,
用密集阵型形成的防御火力 构成一个战斗区域
creating a combat box of defensive fire from a tight formation.
这很重要 因为如果落单
It was important because if we got separated,
德国战斗机就能将我们逐一击落
the German fighters could pick us off one by one.
干掉他们 伙计们
Give 'em hell, boys!
给他们起飞信号吧
Show 'em green.
起飞了 各位
Here we go, fellas.
Sixty.
Ninety.
100.
110.
好 伙计们 起飞了
Okay, boys. Here we go.
Forty.
Fifty.
Sixty.
Ninety.
100 110
100, 110.
还在爬升 伙计们 距离目标三小时
Still climbing, boys. Three hours before we hit the target.
起飞后核对表
After-takeoff checklist.
爬升功率已设定
Climb power is set.
整流罩鱼鳞板正常
Cowl flaps are good.
右起落架收起
Right gear is up.
左起落架收起
Left gear's up.
尾轮收起
Tail wheel up.
好 博塞 你去炮手位置吧
Okay, Bosser, let's get you in the hole.
好 科特 我来驾驶
Okay, Curt, I got control.
飞行员呼叫机组 三千米
Pilot to crew. 10,000 feet.
带上氧气面罩 并答复
Masks on and check in.
球形炮塔收到
Ball turret, roger.
机尾收到
Tail, roger.
右腰收到
Right waist, roger.
左腰收到
Left waist, okay.
无线电通讯员收到
Radio, roger.
工程师收到
Engineer, roger.
导航员确认
Navigator, okay.
投弹手收到
Bombardier, roger.
贝思特 发一颗信号弹
Best, pop a flare.
看看在这么浓的雾里能否列阵
Let's see if we can get into formation in this soup.
收到
Roger that.
那是信号弹吗
Is that a flare?
机鼻呼叫机组 我好像看见正下方有个信号弹
Nose to crew, I think I saw a flare right below us.
收到 看见是从哪发射的吗
Copy. You see who it came from?
没有 外面什么都看不到
Negative. I can't see a thing out there.
天啊 B17 12点方向 低位 他们就在我们下方
Holy shit! B-17 12:00 low. They're right below us.
罗伊 拉起来
Roy, pull up!
该死 我们头顶上有个飞行堡垒
Damn it! There's a fort on top of us.
收到 我看见了
Roger. I see him.
尾炮手 跟我说说
Tail gunner, talk to me back there.
该死的 我们安全了吗
Goddamn it, are we clear?
机尾呼叫飞行员 我们安全了
Tail to pilot, we're clear.
-天啊 好险 -那是克莱文的飞机
-Jesus. That was close. -That's Cleven's fort.
我在哪都能认出他的剃须水
I'd know that aftershave anywhere.
你认真的
Are you serious?
是你叫他飞近点的
I mean, you told him to stay close.
也不能这么近啊
Not like that.
飞行员呼叫机组 我们还要一小时 才能爬出这片云雾
Pilot to crew, we got another hour climbing through this muck.
眼睛都睁大点
Keep your eyes peeled.
天啊 我们得追上其他飞机
Christ. We need to catch up to the rest of the group.
我们落后太多了 阵型一团糟
We're way behind. Formation's a mess.
一号引擎运转不正常
Engine one running rough.
-要坏掉了 -该死
-We're losing it. -Shit.
飞行员呼叫机尾炮手 后面能看到什么吗
Pilot to tail gunner. What can you see back there?
机尾呼叫克莱文 我们大队里 有六架在阵型中
Tail to Cleven, from our group we've got six in formation.
351大队排好了 但349大队 在后面很远的地方 全部六架都是
The 351st is lined up but the 349th is way back. All six of 'em.
看起来维尔那架领头机在冒烟
Looks like their lead, Veal, is trailing smoke.
收到
Roger.
红肉中队领队 这里是表面中队领队
Redmeat Lead, this is Surface lead.
维尔 你那里什么情况
What's going on back there, Veal?
表面中队领队 引擎出故障了 正在想办法
Surface Lead, having engine problems. Working on it.
收到 你得做个决定 维尔
Roger. You need to make a decision, Veal.
你这样会害中队陷入危险
You're putting your squadron in jeopardy.
漫步者领队 收到
Pacer Lead, roger.
长官 我们落后大部队很远了
Sir, we're miles behind the group.
我们等得越久 他们追上去就越久
The longer we wait, the longer it'll take for them to catch up.
该死的 关掉它
Goddamn it. Shut it down.
切断燃料
Cutting fuel. Feather that prop.
漫步者领队 这里是红肉中队领队
Pacer Lead, this is Redmeat Lead.
我们的一号引擎坏了
We've lost engine one.
跟不上这个速度 我们掉头回去了
Can't maintain this pace. We're headed back.
收到 表面中队领队
Copy, Surface Lead.
红肉中队副领队 我们遇到了机械故障
Redmeat Deputy, we have mechanical failure.
我掉头回去了 你来领队
I'm heading back. Lead is all yours.
收到 遵命
Roger, wilco.
飞行员呼叫机组 我们来当红肉中队领队
Pilot to crew, we're taking Redmeat Lead position.
提高到最大巡航速度
Go to maximum continuous power.
注意监视燃料消耗
Monitor our consumption.
我们为了追赶大部队 会消耗很多燃料
We're gonna burn a lot of fuel catching up with the rest of the group.
-开火 -开火
-Fire! Fire! -Fire!
开始了 高射炮开火了 稳住 伙计们
Here we go. Flak incoming. Hold on, boys.
球炮塔呼叫机组 高射炮 11点方向 低位
Ball to crew, flak, 11:00 low.
高射炮 10点方向 高位 4点方向 高位
Flak 10:00 high. Four o'clock high.
到处都是高射炮
Flak, everywhere.
我们谦卑地祈祷 愿上帝惩罚他
May God rebuke him, we humbly pray.
天国的王子啊 你当如此
And do thou, O Prince of the heavenly host,
以上帝的力量 将撒旦打入地狱
by the power of God, thrust into hell Satan.
导航员 目标的预计到达时间
Navigator, what's the ETA for our target?
大约11分钟
About 11 minutes.
-收到 -11分钟
-Roger. -Eleven minutes?
天主和所有邪灵
The heavenly host, and all the evil spirits--
天啊
Holy shit!
他们在地球上游荡 试图毁灭灵魂 阿门
Who wander through the Earth, seeking the ruin of souls. Amen.
该死
Shit.
投弹手呼叫指挥飞行员 我们应该在目标上空了
Bombardier to command pilot, we should be over the target
但我什么都看不到 要投弹吗
but I can't see a damn thing. Should I drop?
不行
It's no good.
-长官 -如果看不到目标
-Sir? -I am not dropping bombs
就不准投弹
if we can't see the damn target.
导航员 第二目标怎么样
Navigator, how does the secondary target look?
导航员呼叫指挥飞行员 一样
Navigator to command pilot, the same.
什么都看不见 长官
Zero visibility, sir.
指挥飞行员呼叫机组 我要终止这次任务
Command pilot to crew, I'm scrubbing this mission.
-导航员 准备新航向 -收到
-Navigator, prepare a new heading. -Roger.
佐特西装二号领队呼叫佐特西装二号
Zootsuit Two Lead to Zootsuit Two.
收到 U F X
Roger. Uncle. Fox. Xray.
重复 收到 U F X
Repeat. Roger. Uncle. Fox. Xray.
-该死 指挥官终止任务了 -见鬼
-Damn it, CO's scrubbing. -Shit!
表面领队呼叫漫步者领队 收到 遵命
Surface Lead to Pacer Lead, roger, wilco.
飞行员呼叫机组 任务终止 重复 任务终止
Pilot to crew, mission scrubbed. Repeat, mission scrubbed.
高射炮停火了
Flak stopped.
你们懂的 伙计们
You know what that means, boys.
好 做好准备 各位
Okay. Get ready, fellas.
收到 少校
Roger that, Major.
指挥飞行员呼叫机尾 后面能看到什么吗
Command pilot to tail, what do you see back there?
我看不到349大队 他们还是落后很远
I can't get a read on the 349th. They're still way back.
克莱文的大队离我们很近
Cleven's group is close and tight with us.
收到 注意看敌军战斗机
Roger that. Keep an eye out for enemy fighters.
随时会进入战斗 伙计们 眼睛都睁大点
Any second now, boys. Keep your eyes peeled.
顶炮塔呼叫机组 12点方向 高位 战斗机
Top turret to crew, 12:00 high. Fighters!
天啊 他们速度很快
Jesus, they're fast.
他朝维尔的中队去了
He's going after Veal's crew.
战斗机 12点方向 高位
Fighters, 12:00 high!
该死
Fuck.
他们打中了亚当斯 不 他们必须跳伞
They got Adams. Oh, no. No. They gotta bail.
亚当斯 跳伞 有人看到降落伞吗
Adams, bail out. Anyone see chutes?
机尾呼叫飞行员 没看到降落伞
Tail to pilot, I don't see any chutes.
收到 继续喊战斗机的位置
Roger. Keep calling out those fighters.
战斗机 12点方向 高位
Fighters! Twelve o'clock high!
施马伦巴赫中弹了
Schmalenbach's hit.
老天 施马伦巴赫被击落了
Oh, Christ. There goes Schmalenbach.
不好 他们直接朝我们来了 天啊
Oh, shit. They're coming straight for us. Jesus.
马林斯
Mullins.
克莱文呼叫机尾 后面什么情况
Cleven to tail, what do you see back there?
机尾呼叫克莱文 349大队在一大朵云里
Tail to Cleven, the 349th are in a cloud bank.
我看不见 长官
I don't see them, sir.
190型战斗机又回来了
190s coming back at us.
战斗机 6点方向 8点方向
Fighters, 6:00. Eight o'clock!
天啊 该死 卡壳了
Oh, man. Fucking jammed.
该死
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
快 快啊
Come on! Come on!
可恶 天啊
Son of a bitch! Jesus Christ.
机尾 报告情况 迪基
Tail, report. Dickie.
机尾呼叫克莱文 战斗机飞走了
Tail to Cleven, fighters are gone.
我看到349大队只剩两架飞机了 长官 三个飞行堡垒不见了
I only see two left from the 349th, sir. Three forts are gone.
迪基 重复一遍
Dickie, repeat.
349大队只剩两架飞机了 长官
There's only two left from the 349th, sir.
天啊
Jesus.
球炮塔呼叫飞行员 长官 他们在炮塔上打出了个洞
Ball turret to pilot. Sir, they shot a hole in the turret.
我快冻死了 谁能把我弄出去吗
I'm freezing to death. Can somebody get me out of here?
嘿 各位 把博塞弄出来取暖
Hey, guys, get Bosser out of there and warm him up.
博塞 在后面还好吗
Bosser okay back there?
我们在照顾他 长官
We're working on him, sir.
你的飞行服都破了 难怪
Your suit's all shot up. No wonder.
给他拿张毯子来
Get him a blanket.
坚持住 伙计们
Hang in there, boys.
我们把炸弹丢进运河后就直接回基地
We'll be back at base right after we dump these bombs in the channel.
没有动力 它终于彻底坏掉了
No power and then she just finally gives up on us completely.
少校 第一次任务的运气真不好
Some tough luck on your first mission, Major.
化油器混合气连接 导致火花塞积累污渍并堵塞
The carburetor mixture link caused a spark plug to load up and foul.
几小时应该就可以修好
It should just take a few hours to fix.
7 8 9 10 11 12 13 14 15
Seven, eight, nine, ten, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15.
-我们来救你 -走 快
-We got you. We got you. -Let's go. Go.
来
Come on.
坚持一下
Stay tight.
该死
Shit.
上校
Colonel?
上校 你还好吗
Colonel, are you okay?
天啊 长官 你还好吗
Oh, geez. Are you okay, sir?
指挥官需要救助
CO needs help!
没有更多飞机回来了
There's no more coming.
-我数了15架 -我也是
-I count 15. -Same.
起飞了19架 一架提前返回 少了三架
Nineteen took off, one returned. Three missing.
-都是维尔中队的 -走吧
-They're all from Veal's squad. -Come on.
-具体数字 长官 -回头说
-Here's the numbers, sir. -Not now.
好 快上卡车
Okay. Get in the fucking truck.
范诺伊 嘿 格兰
Van Noy! Hey! Glen! Glen!
嘿 维尔 冷静点
Hey, Veal. Veal, calm down.
都闭嘴 上卡车
Mouths shut. Get in the truck.
别说了 留着审问时说吧
Not another word, not another word. Save it for the interrogation.
-范诺伊 别说了 上卡车 -现在就去审问
-Van Noy, nothing. On the truck. -Get to interrogation now.
-别说了 -我只想弄清楚
-Not another word. -I'm just trying to find out
-我手下兄弟们怎么样了 -去审问
-what fucking happened to my boys. -Get to interrogation.
立刻 这是命令
Now! That's an order.
走吧 上车 哥们
Come on. Get on, man.
你们看什么呢 有飞机要修呢
What are you looking at? You got a fort to patch up.
-继续干活了 伙计们 -走
-Back to work, boys. -Let's go!
开工 走吧
Let's do it. Let's go.
开车吧 别说话
Let's get the truck moving. No talking!
是 没坠毁真是奇迹
Yeah. Freaking miracle it didn't go down.
-看看这宝贝 -是啊
-Look at this baby. -Yeah.
都成筛子了
Shredded to shit.
-这要修理一阵子了 -我们把它修好
-This'll take a while. -Let's fix it up.
没人来
Ain't nobody came.
我们得更换
We gotta replace it...
我不知道
I don't know. I don't know about that.
没用襟翼降落
No-flap landing.
马达被打坏了
Motor was shot.
我得送你去审问 巴克 走吧
I need to get you to interrogation, Buck. Come on.
一颗炸弹都没投下
Didn't drop a single bomb.
我不得不把炸弹都扔进运河
I had to salvo them over the channel.
我知道
I know.
走吧
Let's go.
你为什么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
什么
What?
你飞过任务了
You've been up.
两次
Two missions.
你没告诉我会是这样
You didn't tell me it was like that.
我不知道该说什么
I didn't know what to say.
你现在亲眼见过了
You've seen it now.
我不知道我看见了什么
I don't know what I saw.
30个人
Thirty guys...
就
Just--
我应该跟你们一起飞的
I should have been up there with you.
我们今后的路还长
We got a long road ahead of us.
是
Yeah.
(下集预告)
(退还希特勒)
我很佩服你们美国人 光天化日在天上飞
I admire you Americans. You're up there in broad daylight.
但白天轰炸等于自杀
But bombing during the day is suicide.
看来你喜欢在晚上战斗啊 布莱恩
Seeing as you like to do your fighting at night, Bryan.
晚上能够击中目标
Who can hit their target at night!
你感觉到什么了吗 因为我什么都感觉不到
Do you feel anything? Because me? I don't feel a thing.
我们有麻烦了 少校
We have a problem, Major.
-我能飞 -你能才怪
-I can fly. -The hell you can.
-我们今天领飞 -我不能领飞
-We're leading the Wing today. -I can't lead a wing.
高射炮 12点方向 同高
Flak, 12:00 level.
三号引擎严重受损
Engine three has been hit bad.
机尾呼叫克莱文 比迪克中弹了
Tail to Cleven. Biddick's been hit.
-准备迫降 -太低了
-Prepare for crash landing. -Too low. Too low.
飞行员呼叫机组 扶稳了
Pilot to crew. Brace yourselves.